







Specializes in establishing and leading technology organizations, engagements, and programs to promote and

develop solutions for the various industries like Financial Services/Utilities/Resources/Products. Cultivates strong relationships to translate



Total Experience: 18 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Highest Degree: MCA[Computers]

Current Designation: Technology Delivery and Program

Manager

Current Company: Accenture

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Chennai Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance

Role: Program Mgr

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Technology Delivery, Program Manager, Project Management, Delivery Management, Program Management, Technology Management, Delivery Management, People Management, Cloud Computing, Resource Allocation, ERP Implementation, Java, Hadoop, Devops

Verified : L Phone Number | Email - id

Last Modified: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Agoal-driven leader with 17+ years' qualitative experience in the areas of Technology Delivery Management, Agile Project Management, Account Management, Program Management, Presales, Automation and Software Development.

Awarded Accenture's Prestigious ACE (Accenture Celebrate Excellence) award 8 times in both Individual and Team categories.

Have International experience in managing large enterprise projects over 3 years in Chemicals (DuPont eBusiness), 8 years in Banking (Bank of America), 3 years in Utilities (Duke Energy, Charlotte) and 2 years in ERP Implementation/Capability Development.

Currently associated with Accenture Services, Hyderabad as Technology Delivery/Program Manager managing multiple projects with >10 Million USD/year revenues with a team of 100+ resources. Responsible for Technology Delivery, controlling program costs, requirements control, UAT and People management, Client Relationship, Growth etc.

Work Experience

 Accenture as Technology Delivery and Program Manager Jan 2004 to Till Date

Key Functions

- Client Engagement Program Management
- Delivery Management Project Management
- Pre-sales/ Business Analysis Client Relationship Management
- Service Management Change Management
- Capability Development Quality Assurance

Deliverables

Spearheading Program & Project Management including planning, scheduling, scoping, monitoring & controlling, capacity planning for releases & defining release plan

Conducting risk identification, defect management, metrics management, reporting & documentation and client engagement

Assessing cost, contingency and arriving at a price, delivering within defined cost, for agreed scope Leading commercial sign-off on project including work order, pricing, scope of project, and delivery dates

Mentoring cross-functional teams and career development and performance appraisals Transforming the teams to Digital Technologies like Artificial Intelligence/Machine Learning, RPA, DevOps, Agile etc.

Organization: Accenture, Client Name: IFS AB (Industrial and Financial Systems)

Duration: Jan 2019 to till date

Role: Program Manager/Agile Delivery Manger, Hyderabad, India

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld. Leading the team of 100 resources and responsible in delivering the solutions implemented for various clients using multiple versions of IFS ERP Product (Developed on .Net & Java Environments and Integrations using BizTalk).

Lead the Program Delivery using both Scrum Framework and Kanban methodologies.

Managed the financials of Revenue 8 Million USD/Year.

Has Experience in managing CDP and Information Security for the Account.

Responsible in delivery for the IFS Clients in collaborating with IFS Counterparts in Sri Lanka, Sweden, other Scandinavian regions.

Driven the Capability growth in developing the Assets and Innovation for the IFS Product.

Involved in RFP's and supported Solution Architect from Delivery Perspective.

Part of Automation Strategy at Client implemented RPA using Blue Prism and Test Automation using TOSCA

Lead a project of migrating Integrations on Biztalk to Azure Cloud.

Organization: Accenture, Client Name: Bank of America, NA

Duration: July 2010 to Dec 2018

Environment: Portfolio of Projects

Role: Delivery/Program Manager, Charlotte, NC & Hyderabad, India

Tech. Delivery/Program Manager - Java/J2EE/RPA/Al - Capital Markets, Mortgage, Consumer

Technology and Risk Domains

Jan 2018 - Dec 2018

Program Manager for Capital Markets Domain (F&OTC, Trading, Sales Research)

Successfully implemented one Portal for 25 to 30 Capital Markets applications using LifeRay and

DevOps which has helped the clients to host all the applications in one place.

Played the Scrum Master Role for a team of 45+ resources in developing the application

of Scrums with the duration of 4 weeks and 6 weeks

Identifying the use cases and implementing them with latest technologies like RPA to increase the productivity and to reduce the day to day regular tasks.

Instrumental in implementing Email Classification Engine in tracking and prioritizing the millions of emails that were exchanged between clients and operations teams from Trading and Post Trade Services domains. Identified and implemented prioritization and classification using Supervised Machine Learning.

Streamlining the Entitlements Process using RPA to update the Roles and Responsibilities of the existing applications

Portfolio Lead/Program Manager - Hyderabad, India

Oct 2014- Dec 2017

Lead the team of 200+ resources across shores and responsible in delivering 60+ Applications in various streams like App Development, Automation, Prod Support, Transformation, DevOps etc using Agile methodologies

Started the Enterprise Technology Architecture program from Scratch and grown the team size to 60 in duration of 6 months and delivered the technologies like TOSCA BPM, DevOps, Agile etc.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Computers) from Nagarjuna University in 1999

 ${\sf PG: MCA\,(Computers)\,from\,Periyar\,University\,in\,2002}$

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Professional Scrum Master PSM1 Mcrosoft Azure fundamentals

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Java, JEE, Spring, Hibernate		
IBMWPS, Sawion BPM, Pega PRPC		
Appian BPM, DevOps, Unix Shell Scripting		
Automation (Selenium/TOSCA)		
Hadoop, DevOps, RPA, Cloud Migration		
Agile/Scrum		
Spring Boot(Zuul, Eureka, AppDynamics)	2019	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

5 5				
Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Telugu				
Tamil				
Kannada				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.